너 그 미래학자 알아?앨도스 리키 박사
아니
신진화는 우리에게자기유도적 진화의
기회를제공해줍니다
델피네야코지마야그 애는 내가 안다는걸
모른다는거야
내가 그애를 감시하는사람인거지이게 진짜 어떤건지
인정할 때가 됐잖아?
나 크게 실수한거야?나 가야겠다
높은데서 일어나는일이라고, 사라불법적인
인간복제 시도
넌 아홉이 있고..아냐! 난 단 하나뿐이야당신네
문제가 생겼어
어떤 문제인가요?이건 베스가 아니네당신이 올리비에군
우리를 죽이는 자는
우크라이나 출신에금발이야종교에 미친애지
네가 바로 원형이다네가 바로 빛이다
나 우리가 친구인꿈을 꿨어우리 친구 아니거든
그렇게 될꺼야
그녀를 잡았어요앨도스여행 준비를 시켜두게
아침에 그리 가도록 하지
당신 꼬리가보고싶은데
베스 차일즈에 대해얘기할게 있어요
베스 차일즈?어서 가
잘못 걸었어요
그 연립주택엔돌아갈 수 없어안전하지 못해
놈들이 우릴 찾을꺼야
아트이거 꼭 봐야돼사라 매닝은
누구지?
준비됐어?
너 도플갱어란거믿어? 앤지?일을 혼란하게
만드려고
도플갱어들이설치고 다닌다고? 아니쌍둥이라면?
베스가 쌍둥이얘기한적 있어?
젠장 그럼뭐란 말이야?
이봐, 신원미상 피해자가사라 매닝이라는게확인됐잖아
그러니
일어나가정방문이나 하자고
저기이거 일단
우리끼리만 알고있자고
어떻게 돌아는건지확인할때 까지만그래, 그러지
그래나한테도 낫겠네고마워
그 연립주택엔돌아가지도 못하고
어-우쉬 쉬 쉬..
올리비에의 상관인리키 박사가오늘 날라와서
당신을 찾을꺼야
됐어
잠깐이라도, 내가복제인간인거 잊었었는데
그자는 네가 복제인간들을죽이고 다니는줄 안다고
오, 미안보니와 클라이드* 한텐
라떼는 없다(유명 도망자 커플)
좋은 아침, 피
제발 이거태워버리면 안될까?
뭐?네 미친 여동생 코트에서
바다 냄새 나거든
필릭스!사라 여기서 한동안
숨어 지내야 되겠거든
당신도? 내 영감에악영향을 끼치거든
내 침대에서부벼대고
앨리슨와, 잘됐다! 걔도 초대해
그럼, 식이요법 하는 사람들끼리
다들 모여서 껴안고"그레이 아나토미"나 보지안녕, 부부동반 모임은
어땠어?
난 일찍 왔어코지마가 벌써
있었던 일 알려줬고
난 너희 둘 좀잊고 쉬고 있지우리 집에서
좀 모이자
어, 이게 그결혼 상담 같은거
아니겠지?
도니하고 나이혼할꺼야뭐?
오, 난 괜찮아내가 결심한거야
전부 다잘되가고 있어됐다
이제 걱정된다
저기, 그러지마알아서 챙길 수 있거든그럴 필요는..
넌 거짓말쟁이감시자들을정리하는거나 도와줘
앨리슨, 누가 네감시자인지 모르잖아?너무 집착하지마
내 생활을 돌려받고싶어, 사라제발 그것만은
존중해줘
앤슬리여기서 뭐하는거야?
앨리슨,집에 있었네!나 일찍 올거라고
얘기했잖아
오늘은 아니였지바보같긴화분에 물 좀
주려고 들렸어
그런거?
제가 나갈께요!
얘야 얘야 얘야너가 현관나갈 때는 언제라고
얘기했었지?
우리가 누구초대했을때에요아-하, 그럼
초대했니? 안했니?
키아라방에 올라가라
어서
쇼반 새들러 씨?물어보시는
분은요?
벨 형사와디앤젤리스 형사입니다사라 매닝의
법적 보호자 되시죠?
Orphan Black 01x08Entangled Bank
Original Air Date May 18, 2013
한글자막 :  Nike Plus
사라가 죽었어요?
유감입니다
어떻게요?총에 맞았어요
총이요?
언제요?
11월 25일 정도에요
11월 25일요?2주 전이잖아요신원확인에 시간이
좀 걸렸네요
헌데 확실히애가 맞아요?
사라가 누구와어떤 문제라도있었는지
아시나요?
특히나, 여자들요꼭 여자들만
아니더라도요
그건 왜여쭈시는거죠?
죄송해요수사에 관련된건
말씀드릴 순 없습니다
지금 바로는요부인과 여기서
같이 살았었나요?
아뇨, 나이가 됐죠1년전에 나갔어요저희가 별로..
별로 가깝진않았어요
사라에게자매가 있나요?
아뇨그앤 고아였어요
자매가 있을수도 있나요?그랬었다면
우리 둘한테도
새로운 소식이였겠죠
신진화는 헛소리야코지마아니,
그렇지 않거든. 사라
내가 하는 일에있어서엄청난 잠재력을
가진 응용철학이야
그래서 너도 네실험물들을
암시장에 내놓게?
그땐 정체를 파악하지못해서잖아, 그치?올리비에는 널
살인자로 여겼다고, 사라
그렇지, 머, 네 좋은 친구인리키 박사님이 오고계시니그자한테도 똑같은걸
기대해도 될까?
됐거든너 알어?우리를 죽이는 사람을
우리를 창조한 사람한테
돌린건 바로 너라고내 말은, 이 뒤죽박죽에
헬레나를 넣어서 어쩌겠단거야?
어이! 상아탑!이렇게 된건 전부네 과학 분석이
틀려서거든
아니, 아니거든맞아, 니가 틀렸어
알았어?
놈들은 의료검사로내가 베스가 아닌걸 알았다고우리 DNA가 동일하다고
니가 그랬잖아
그런거거든있잖아 어쩜너한테 주어진 해맑은 성격
때문이였는지도 모르겠다
빌어먹을 너어디 편이야, 코지마?오, 끊어버려!
걔도 괴상한 리키쪽이야
그..젠장! 피, 코지마가
퍼플 쿨에이드* 마셔버렸어
*맹목적으로 어떤걸 따라함
그러면야걘 그냥 냅둬앨리슨은 아직
구할 수 있을꺼야
앨리슨은괜찮아
안괜찮아도니랑 이혼하잖아뭔 일이 터져도
자기 탓이지
이혼은 진짜 이상한 것들도정상으로 되버려, 사라거짓된 행복도
잃게되고
쇼핑몰 가는 길도잊어버리겨그리고는, 시내로 가서
자기 자신을 찾지
걔 자기 친구년들
중에 하나를 감시자라생각하고 있어앤슬리
그 여자야, 확실해
휴, 이혼이라불쌍하다
애들은 어딨어?우리 엄마 집에
애들도 알아?애들한테 얘기했어?너 질문이 너무 많다
안그래?
그래, 당연하지널 걱정하니까
너가 행복하지않다는건 알았지만..어떻게
알았단거야?
물어보고다녔겠지언제나
묻고 또 묻고
전부다 알지나에대해 캐묻고 다녔으니
생각나서 그런데..오늘 저녁에 내가
피겨스케이트 코치하면 안될까?
애들도 어머니랑있겠다하루밤 쉬라고
진정하고
아니, 너나 진정해피겨스케이트는내 차례거든
내 딸이 오던 안하던
난 나갈꺼야앨리, 가끔 "네"시간도
필요할거 같아서
그래서 너도 우리집 열쇠를돌려줄 필요가 있겠네뭐?!
내가 어쨌다고?
열쇠, 돌려주실까
고통스럽단건알아그러니 내 열쇠는
돌려달라고 안할께
그러니난 널 버리진않을꺼란거 알아줘
앨리
있지..
형님의 부속물을복구하는건, 어..
도저히 불가능할 것같습니다꼬리의 소상이
너무 심해서요
선생님께서는처음보시는 거겠군요예, 이거 대단히
놀랍군요, 사실..
이정도 수준의외과작업이라면..어쨌든
지나치게 잘했군요
여기 얼마나 오래있어야될까요?혈액 손실된거나
그..
부분에 감염 위험을고려하면며칠에서
일주일 정도요
감사합니다선생님전 형이 깰 때까지
기다리죠
코지마랑은어디까지 갔나?
가까워졌어요
그애..
저한테 수작을 걸더군요앨도스
정말로?
예
델피네
코지마의 안전이위험한 상태야다른 대상물들도
그렇고
그녀가 누구와연락을 하고 있는지
알아야만해
그래도 그애가 뭔가드러내보여야죠
드러내길 기다리란게아니거든직접적인 위협이 있잖나
그러니 네가
더 빨리 더 깊이파보라는 거지
"사랑하는 엄마보고싶어요
S 아줌마는 엄마가엄만 햇살 좋은데
계시데요..
집에 돌아와주세요
사랑해요
키아라"
어이! 제발 그러지말아줄레?나 너랑은
숨어있기 안할레
제대로 좀 앉아냄새나냐?
그래!발냄새 나거든니 발이라서
더 지독하거든
앨리슨전화 안받네
누가 전화한거?
아트야, 또미안해요, 베스는 이제
여기 안살아요
아니지걔 나랑 살거든
걔 장난감남친이자경호원이지
그만! 제발그만 좀 해줄레?
제발..어이-어이, S 부인
어이-어이
그래도너 살아있네그쵸, 왜요?
강력반 형사 둘이 아침에집 현관에 와서는
니 시체를 자갈 분쇄기에서찾았다고확신에 차있더라
미모사* 드실분?(오렌지쥬스 칵테일)
아가리 닥치고 앉아!
내가 유골을 달라해서그걸 토스트에 얹어서너희 둘한테
먹이고 싶어졌었는데
나한테 깨우침을좀 주지 않으렴?아줌마한테 거짓말
하고 싶진 않아서요..
아직 안되요
뭐라고 하던가요?별로 없어
나도 조금만 조심해서 말했지그게 다다
고마워요
뭐가 어떻게 되던지키아라한테
한발자국만 다가와도불같이 소리쳐라
그 집은이 나라에 와서우릴 위해
지은거였고
해야한다면다 불태워 버릴 수 있다
약속할께요
안녕안녕, 안면 재구성이
거의 다되가
그래, 그치맘 단단히 먹어엄청난 거야해
사라 매닝은 자청해서헉슬리 역에서기차 앞에
뛰어들었어
뭐라고?!
사망시간 봐바
총맞은 피해자보다이틀 전이네
신원미상 피해자는사라 매닝이 아니네사라 매닝은 벌써
죽었었고
지문이 맞다는거만빼면 말이지쌍둥이 맞지? 쌍둥이
쌍둥이들 지문은
일치로 나올 정도로비슷하거든그 얘긴, 환경적 요소
예를 들면
닳은거나 상처로만보통 구분되거든좋아, 그래도 양모는
친척이 없다고 했잖아
그분이아시는 한에지사라는
고아였잖아
베스는 태어날때 갈라진세쌍둥이란거지왜그래, 맞장구 좀 쳐줘
한 이틀 만에
같은 도시에서, 하나는 자살하나는 살해 당했다고?그 얘기는 말이지
걔들은 연락이 닿아있었어
더 이상 따로 지내지않았단 뜻이야, 그렇지?그리고 그걸 확인해줄
사람이 딱 하나 남았지
베스!
예, 연락 받았어요
지금 괜찮아요?
그래 무슨 일이세요?벌써 제가
보고싶어지셨어요?
신원미상 사건에서네가 작업한데
몇가지 의문점이나타나서
어떤거요?
저기, 너 우리한테피해자 지문이일치하는게 없었다고
했었잖아
예, 없었죠
근데, 사건 서류철에그걸 확인 할만한게
전혀 없더라고
있어야 하는데
그래, 우리가 다시 돌려봤거든일치하는게 있더라고
그렇게 결국 어딘가는닿게 되는거거든예, 그런거 같네요
확인해야 될게있는데..
장난하시는거에요?
사라 매닝이라는이름이 너한테
무슨 의미가 있을까?
젠장 이건누구에요?전에 그 여자
본적 있어?
어, 어, 예그럼요거울 속에서요
왜이러세요없죠!이봐, 난 닮은 사람들이
있다고 보거든
그런거야?
앨리슨!앨리슨
너 좀 어때?
응?오, 자기 안됐다
필요한거 있으면말만 해내가 뭐 좀
하려고 하면
그냥 지원해 주면 안돼?나한테 중요한 거란 말야그냥 맞춰입는다고
코치가 되는게 아니잖아
당신이 코치가 아니라고자기가 뭐하고 있는지도 모르잖아내가 매번 여기서..
앨리! 어서와!
안녕하세요채드
독신오셨네요자유로우시죠, 예?여기서 뭐하는거야
앤슬리?
내말이, 그쵸?
채드, 가서아령이나 가지고 놀아이번엔 내가
맡겠다고 했잖아
너도 애들 코치할만한상태는 아니고다친데다 아주 소금을
문지르는군, 앤지
미안할만큼 했다
나 완전히 괜찮거든그리고 누구 하나 너한테
나대신 해달란 사람없었어. 가봐앨리슨, 니가 화난건
도니잖아, 내가 아니라고
나 내버려두라고얘기했다난 네가 네가
아니라고 얘기했지
너 뭐하는 건지다 알거든, 앤슬리내 인생
망쳐놓고 싶은거야?
내가 널망쳐놔 주지
이렇게 못되게굴어서 미안하네그래도 네가
신원미상의 지문과
너와의 관계를 묻어버리려고했던거 같거든무슨 관계요?
전 자매도 없고요이 사람이
누군지도 모른다고요
사라 매닝은고아였지신원미상자와
지문이 같지, 근데
신원미상이 살해되기이틀 전에 자살했거든
이봐, 베스우린 네가 맞는지만
알면 되거든
이애 기록 좀볼 수 있어요?
미안해넌 민간인이잖아
예, 선배가 늘원하시던거죠
아트, 저 지금변호사 세워야되요?
나야 모르지베스
그런거야?
감식반에 최대한 빨리얘 지문돌려보라고 해
그래야지
오, 젠장
예, 좋아요딱 걸렸네요제발 부탁인데 앤슬리한테
꼰지르지만 말아요
이런데 마누라가 얼마나지랄할지 아시죠?
와우
앨리슨있죠, 채드
대학때 "갓스펠"* 했을때
이후에 처음으로 가네요*godspell-뮤지컬 연극
그게 뭔지모르거든요
좋네요
더 있으세요?
폴
두어시간 있으면앨도스 리키 박사가도착할꺼죠
당신한테문자 보냈더군요
자넨 적어도두명의복제인간들하고
일을 꾸몄지
실제로 하나죠정신 나갔나?
보기와는 달리여기서 자리가위태로운 사람은
내가 아니거든, 폴
당신 말이야
전직 군 정보 대원한테지저분 한 일하라고협박을 한거거든
올리비에 듀발..
꽤 세련된 필명이야형씨
고맙네
당신 진짜 이름은케빈이지
워싱턴, 웰나치출신이고구린내 나는 성범죄 영장이
한 무더기더군
조직에서도알고 있어그치, 근데
경찰은 모르거든
그러니 내가어제 밤에 일어난 일을
얘기해줄테니잘 들으라고
오, 이거야지붕으로
연기를 뺀다..
빨리 사라지는군요
공기 청정제덜 뿌리고요공기 청정해서
말인데..
드디어 당신 코치하는데도니를 떼놓은거축하드려요
지금 제 결혼이파탄났는데
놀리는거에요채드?죄송요
미안해 마세요
당신, 앤슬리랑오후 약속
정확히 잡지 않은거알아요에, 아시죠
당신이나 나는말이죠, 헤드릭스..응?
우린 상어에요..움직이지 않으면, 죽죠
머, 그점은확실하네요소매없는 티에
밤늦게 조깅도하고
당신도 그렇게나쁘진 않잖아요
단단한 둔근에멋진 흉근
절 가지고 벤치프래스도하실 수 있으시면서별거아니죠
절 공 튀기듯하실 수도 있고요
그럼요
너무 많이하신거 같은데
당신이모자른가 보네요여기, 우리
뭐하고 있는거죠?
당신을 대상으로보고 있죠성적으로
도니한테갚아주려고요진짜 나 이런거
잘 못해야 되는데
근데 안그렇죠
어서와델피네내가 방해한건
아닌지 모르겠네
오, 아냐 아냐아니, 그럴리가그게, 그러니까
내가 이런데
그냥, 머, 결론으로뛰어들었으니그게 있잖아
나도 한번도..
알아, 알아,알아, 너 게이도 아닌거내가 완전 바보였지
정말 미안해
아, 내가..아, 그래
그럼 너..?그래그냥 너랑은, 그런
괴상한 연구나하려고 말야완전 괴상한 연구
그 얘기 들으니 다행이다왠줄 알아?내가 다이아드 연구소를
자세히 알아보고있었는데리키 박사가
이식유전자를 가진 장기이식에
대한 전담 부서를 만들고있다는거 알아? 그래서..미안, 나 좀전에
쥐 실험 모형을
통계분석 하는데애먹고 있었거든뭐?!
그래우-와우
있지, 이거 진짜로진짜로 대단하다이런거 하는 사람을
드뎌 만나보네
날 찍은 사람
그래, 동감이야
확실히
그때 키스한거머리에서 떠나질 않아
그거 나쁘지 않은쪽이지?
어, 그니까나 양성애에 대해선
생각해 본적이 없거든
내 얘긴, 내자신 말야알지?하지만 과학자로선
성적취향의 다양성은이해하지그래도, 있잖아
사회적 편견들
그런게 성적요소를규정하고 있잖아생물학적 요소들에
반하는 거잖아
너도 알지?으-흠, 그거
희안하게 낭만적이다
완전 고무되는데
오, 이런!
내가 코치해주길원해? 어!
어서!예!
그만, 안돼
애들아 여기는돌아가자코치님, 예!
결승점에 들어왔어예, 코치님 만세!
이겼다!
내려!
너 내 남편이랑뒹구는거 미라가 봤어!다들 안다고!
내 남편이랑 뒹굴어!
머, 어쩌면니가 나보다는 남편한테
더 신경을 썼어야지
차에서 내려앨리슨!
너 지금누굴 상대하는건지나
알고나 있어?!
알거든, 니가 뭔지확실히 알지넌 추잡한
염탐꾼에 감시자야
추잡해?어처구니가 없네
그게 남 뒤통수나치는 미친 창녀가할 소리야!
니가 감히너...
그만해!
이거놔!
하-하!악!
안녕 안녕 안녕
영안실오빠
사라 매닝에 대해전부 내놔봐요
백인 여성이고열차로 자살했죠
당신이 시체와 인도를처리했죠저 엄청 많은 시체를
처리하거든요
무슨 문제라도요?
자갈 분쇄기에서 나온신원미상 피해자
지문이요
감식반 얘기론서로다른 두 여자의섬뜩하게
똑같다는군요
예, 하나는사라 매닝이고또 하나는..
완전히 다른 여자고요
어디보자어..
사라 매닝열차로 자살
세상에 이런
으스스한데
이 여자 신원확인해준 사람이름하고 주소가
필요해요
뭐라고?! 내..
알았어, 콜린좀 천천히 말해그 사람들, 정확히
뭐라고 했는데?
거짓말 못하겠더라고필릭스, 알지?기록하고, 네 서명,
주소하고 있지
알았어
끊어야겠다넌 뜨겁게
목욕이나 해
나중에얘기하자젠장! 사라
니가 처리할 수있지, 어?경찰? 그럼
나야.. 그럼
넌 어디로갈껀데?
모르겠다
젠장!
필릭스!
나야 나앨리슨!
제발 나 좀재워줘
너 나랑장난하잔거지나한테 나쁜일이
일어났어
그래 나도 진심으로얘기 듣고 싶거든나 근데
지금 당장은
너희들 가야돼뭐야?
거기로돌아갈 수 없어
하루 밤만이야앨리슨
나 앤슬리 남편이랑잤거든
뭐야?
채드랑부벼댔다고
그리곤 앤슬리가길 한복판에서나한테 덤볐어
내 자신도 망가지고애들도 망신시키고
거기 돌아갈 수가없다고내가 널 단단히
우습게 봤었네
그년 혼줄을내줬길 바래
그랬지
그런데로
나 도니랑 이혼하고싶지 않거든근데 계속 거짓말
할수도 없고 애들한테
거짓말 하는것도 싫어다 싫다고!
어떻게 이런 정신나간 짓을버틸 수가 있겠어?
못하지모르겠어, 아트가
날 감옥에 쳐넣거나
코지마가 우릴 약먹여서신진화론자들한테넘겨버리거나
어쩜 또 뭐
헬레나도 잊지마걘 항상 즐겁더라
내가 아는거라곤내가 돌아온건 일을 바로 잡으려고키아라의 진짜 엄마가
되려는거라고
그런거 얘기 하면어떻게 될까?
그말은밝히겠다는 거야?
"저 엄마가
보고싶어요""저 엄마가
보고싶어요"
"저 엄마가보고싶어요""저 엄마가
스콧스번 거리
베이커 박사님소아과로 가주시기 바랍니다
베이커 박사님
내가 보안 영상을복제인간 한명만
보이게 바꿔놨지베스.. 사라..
절대 없었던거야
그분은 똑똑하시거든안통할꺼야
통할꺼야당신은 하나만 얘기해
한명만 있었던거야
그리고 자신을 탓하는건그만둬 주세요
모르는거였잖습니까?
리키 박사님저는..폴 디어든
대단하다고들었네
앨도스 씨
앨도스 씨, 그녀가제 꼬리를 가져갔어요
닥치게나올리비에
너 괜찮아?
그래
정말이야?
나.. 나 남자애들이랑자고나서도 울어
안됐다
그래도 그거 알아?응?
지금껏 이렇게굶주린 적이 없었어
아이스크림 때문이라도누굴 죽일꺼야음, 알았다
네 바램은나한테 명령이지내가 가게에
좀 가서
에스키모 파이를좀 가져와야겠네에스키모?
그래
내가 그건모르는거 같은데몰라?
몰라
단단히 준비해너 거의 그거
중독되 쩔어버릴껄
벌써 그런거 같거든
젠장
바로 눈앞에서 그년이베스인척 하는걸 때려쳤죠
폴을 노린게 아니였다면절 죽였을 겁니다자기 이름이
헬레나라고 했고
슬라브족 억양을가졌더군요그년이 자기가
베스를 죽이고
삶을 가로챘다고인정했습니다앨도스 씨,
완전히 미친년이에요
큰물에서 놀게된걸환영하네
예, 알겠습니다
죄송한데여러분방문시간 끝났어요
아, 그렇죠저희가 자리 비켜드리죠
자넨 쉬면서치료나 받게나
군대에서는이런 말을 하던가"넌 자신의 패기를
증명했다"?
아닙니다그런 말은 안씁니다좋네
그럼, 내일다음 단계에 대해
얘기하는게 좋겠군
실례하지
뭐 좀 찾았어?
코지마의 안전을약속해주세요이 애가 탐구한건
앨도스, 전부 순수하게..
순수하게본능에서에요델피네
믿어주길 바라네난 그앨 보호는거야이제
뭐가 있던가?
저기, 자기 자신만을생물학 연구를 한게 아니라여덟명이 더있다는걸..
알아냈더군요
연락을하고 있던거죠이름들이 필요하네
알았어요, 예, 그게..몇 명은 죽은거 같고요제니카 징거
그래
다니엘 포니에그래
카티야 오블리어그래
헬레나
성은 안나와있네요헬레나
앨리슨 헨드릭스가 있고베스 차일즈그리고
사라 매닝이요
사라 매닝?
그 여자한테다른건 없나?
아니, 없어요
저기요, 가야겠어요곧 돌아올꺼에요, 그럼
푸-후
누구에요?
무슨 일이냐?괜찮은 거야?예, 때가 됐네요
쇼반
진짜로 무슨일이 벌어진건지말씀드릴 때네요
머, 그렇담귀 뚫려있다
쇼반, 이쪽은앨리슨 헨드릭스에요
뵙게되서반갑습니다
그래, 더 얘기해봐라얘야그러니까
인간복제보다 더
이상한거야없겠지예, 저흰
스카브로에 살고요
한 백만년쯤 전에
대학도 다녔어요대학에 다녔다고?
음! 예운동역학과요너 엉뚱하게
다닌데가 어디였더라?
어, 그것도 기본적으론마사지 요법이죠, 아니였나?
아니지, 사라그거 아주
중요한거야
효과있거든
안돼
음, 그 후엔결혼도 했어요
그리고 다 망쳐버렸죠
얘 키아라보러한번 왔었지너 사는데
얘 아니였나?
뭔가 있을줄알았다니까
예, 죄송해요, 그 미친애헬레나요, 절 쫓아왔죠알았다, 그래
헬레나, 앨리슨, 코지마
베스는 경찰관이고예, 자살한 애요
너지아뇨, 우리가 수천명
있을 수도 있어요
으흠! 헬레나가 전부다죽이지만 안는다면야우리 전부
엉망이죠
너만 빼고, 사라내가 거기서
최고로 엉망이거든, 앨리슨
아냐, 아니, 아니넌 "엿먹어"라고 말하잖아내가 오늘 "엿먹어"
라고 했다가
내 인생을 몽땅날려버렸다고난 그냥 "엿같에"
"너나먹어"
그러고 싶었는데내가 엿됐어전부 엿되버렸어
있잖니 얘야이제 너 잘
손님방 둘러보는게좋겠구나, 아가야?어? 어?
이리와라
예, 어너무 다정하세요으흠! 너 있잖니
너 정말 운좋은거야, 사라
우리 엄마라면 이렇게다정하지 않으셨을꺼야. 그분..우리 엄마는 날 어디
치료소에 쳐넣을껄
예, 그래요
사라 맞아요
너무 충격적이였죠시체 처리대에 놓은
누날 보는데
그리 보이는게죽었구나.. 정말
그럼 수양 누나한테다른 자매는 없었나요?저뿐이에요
전 계속해서스스로한테 물어봤죠
"내가 뭘 놓쳤지?"그거 아세요?저 정말로 그런 조짐을
보지 못했었거든요
베스 차일즈응?
그건 누구에요?
제가 좀 봐도괜찮으세요?
미술을 좋아해서
예, 보세요아무렴요
아! 어...그것들은
사라의 다양한면들이에요그 연작들을 전
뒤틀린 누나 라고 하죠다들 좋군요
슬픔을 털어내는방법이죠예
절 어디론가이끌고 가주죠
감사합니다다시 한번,
위로를 전합니다감사합니다
전에도 이런게있었어
그건 무슨 말이야?
여보세요여보세요?
여보세요?하비, 너
능구렁이같은 자식
너인거 다 알거든.
지난밤에, 내가전화를 한통 받았었지영국식 억양에
어떤 펑크족이
베스에 대해서얘기하고 싶다고 했어그리고는
끊어버렸지
녀석 끌고가지녀석 가지를 흔들면 될꺼야
아냐, 너무 일러먼저, 이 일 전체에
더 제대로된 그림부터그려봐야 겠어가자
뭐하는 겁니까?
다리에 감각이없거나 하신가요?아뇨
확인해본 겁니다
좀 쉬세요
아, 그리고 리키 박사님이안부 전하시더군요
여기 이 일들 사이에무언가가
더 있어요뭐냐 니가
필요한게, 사라?
어떻게 도와줄수 있을까?
와우앨리슨, 코지마
베스..
쟤들 어머님들은시험관 아기라도해볼만큼 아이를
원했었죠
그럼, 우리 엄마는왜 절 포기했을가요?
그런 소문이있었다
예?
우리가 숨겨주던아이들 중 몇이칼튼의 거래망에서
들어온 애들 말이다
너같은, 아이들을어둠에 숨겼었는데..그게 정확히
무슨 뜻이죠"어둠에 숨기다"뇨?있잖니
서류기록 없이
사회 제도에넣지 않고..소문은
그런 아이들이
의학실험의대상들이였다는 거였지
칼틀의거래망이라
어떤 종류의실험이죠?모르겠다
얘야
피해망상의 시대였고철저히 소외됐었으니그땐 모든게
소문이거든
칼틀이 널 내게데려왔지
그분이 제 생모를알고 있지 않았을까요?아마도, 그치만
그랬었더라도
나한테 얘기안했을지도 모르지
연락되는 분들이그분 아는 사람은요?
가..가능은 하지
그분하고 연락이닿을 수 있을까요?15년이나 됐지
내가 마지막으로 들은건원우드 스크럽 교도소에 있다더라연락 해보마
제가 누구인지만알고 싶은거에요
넌 그대로 너란다
그걸 잊지마라넌 살아남았잖니
키아라?
헬레나에요!키아라!
키아라!
우리 어디가요?
누굴 만나러가는거야
넌 어떻게 사라의 딸이된거지, 꼬마야?
어떻게 그게가능해?키아라!
멈춰!아줌마 꼭
우리 엄마같아요
아니, 아니다
너희 엄마는진짜가 아니야
우리 엄마진짜 맞아요
키아라!
헬레나?
왜, 천사야?
아줌마는 무슨 일이있었어요?
나도 몰라
키아라!
키아라!저 이제 집에
가야겠어요
그래
가는 길 알지?
당연하죠
잘자라, 천사야
키아라!엄마!
키아라, 안돼!
안돼!
Do you know this futurist,Dr. Aldous Leekie?
No.
Neolution gives usthe opportunity
at self-directedevolution.
- Delphine.- Cosima.
Because she doesn'tknow that I know.
I'm  the one who'smonitoring  her.
It's time we admit whatthis is really about?
Did I make a huge mistake?
I have to go.
This is high-level shit, Sarah,
an illegal human cloning trial.
There's nine of you. No!There's only one of me.
You have a problem.
- What kind of a problem?- She's not Beth.
You must be Olivier.The one who's killing us
is Ukrainian, she's blonde,
she's a religious nut.
You arethe original.
You are the light.
I dreamed that we were friends.
- We're not friends.- We will be.
I have her, Aldous.
Get her ready to travel.I'll be there in the morning.
I want to see
your tail.
Aaaaah!
I need to talk to you about Beth Childs.
Beth Childs?
Let's go.Wrong number.
We can't go backto the townhouse.
It's not safe. They'llbe looking for us.
Art, you got to see this.
Who's Sarah Manning?
Ready for this?
You believe indoppelgangers, Angie?
Doppelgangers running around
to confusethe issue? No.
How about twins?
Beth ever mentiona twin sister?
What the hell is going on?!
Look, we identifiedSarah Manning
as Jane Doe, so,
come on, we got tomake a house call.
Hey.
You mind keepingthis between us?
Just 'til we figure outwhat the hell it is.
Yeah, sure.
Yeah, sounds good to me.
Thanks.
We can't go backto the townhouse.
Unh-unh.Shh shh shh shh.
Olivier's boss,Dr. Leekie,
is flying in today. He'llbe looking for you.
Okay.
For a second, there,I forgot I was a clone.
He thinks you're the onekilling his clones.
Oh. Sorry.
Couldn't afford lattesfor Bonnie and Clyde.
Morning, Fe.
Can we torch this, please?
What?
Your psycho sister's coatsmells like low tide.
Felix!
Sarah's going to have tohole up here for a while.
You, too? Impingingon my creativity.
Shagging in my bed.
Alison.
Oh, brilliant! Invite her, too.Then, maybe, we can all
cuddle up with weight watchersand "Grey's Anatomy."
Hey. How wascouples' camp?
I came back early.
Cosima filled me in already
and I'm taking a breakfrom you two.
I need to getmy house together.
Uh, isn't that what
marriage counseling was for?
Donnie and I aregetting a divorce.
What?
Oh, I'm fine.
It's my decision.
Everything is under control.
Okay, now, I'm worried.
Well, don't be.I can take care of myself
and I don't need...
You helping me clear my deck
of liars and spies.
Alison, you don't knowwho your monitor is, okay?
Don't fixate.
I'm reclaiming my life, Sarah.
Please respect that.
Aynsley, what are you doing?
Alison, you're home!
I told you I wascoming back early.
But not today, silly.
I just cameto water the plants.
Did you?
I'll get it!
Hey hey hey hey.What have I said
about answering thedoor on your own?
Only when we invite someone.
Uh-huh, and we havenot, have we?
Kira, go up to your room.
Quick.
Siobhan Sadler?
Who wants to know?
Detectives Bell and Deangelis.
Are you the legal guardian
of Sarah Manning?
Orphan Black 01x08Entangled Bank
Original Air Date May 18, 2013
Sarah's dead?
I'm sorry.
How?
She was shot.
Shot?
When?
On or around November 25th.
November 25th?That's 2 weeks ago.
Identification took some time.
But you're sure it's her?
Did you know if Sarahhad any problems
with anyone?
Women, especially,
but not exclusively.
Why would you ask that?
I'm sorry.
We can't share muchabout the investigation,
at this point.
Did she live here with you?
No. She came of age andshe moved out years ago.
We aren't...
We weren't close.
Did Sarah have a sister?
No, she was an orphan.
Could  she have a sister?
If she did, it would be news
to both of us.
Neolution is bullshit, Cosima.
No, it isn't, Sarah.
It's an applied philosophy
with profound implications for what I do.
So you'd go around
blackbagging your subjects?
That was mistaken identity, okay?
Olivier thought youwere the killer, Sarah.
Yeah, well, your good friendDr. Leekie's on his way.
Can I expect the same from him?
Okay, you know what?
You were the onewho turned our killer
against our creators.
I mean, why the hell wouldyou bring Helena into the mix?
Oi! Ivory tower!This all happened
because  you  gotthe science wrong.
No, I didn't.
Yes, you did, okay?
They knew I wasn't Beth,from the medical tests.
You said our DNA was identical.
It is. You know, maybe it was
your sunny personality that gave you away.
Whose bloody sideare you on, Cosima?
Oh, hang up!She's a Freaky Leekie.
D...
Shit! Fe, Cosima drankthe purple kool-aid.
Well, then, to hell with her.
You can still save Alison.
Alison's fine.
She's not fine.She's divorcing Donnie.
Every freakfor herself.
Divorces do really strangethings to normals, Sarah.
They lose their fake happiness,
they forget the wayto the mall,
and then, they come downtownto find themselves.
She's obsessing that one
of her bitchy friendsis her monitor.
Aynsley.
It's her, for sure.
Whew, divorce.You poor thing.
Where are the kids?
They're at my mother's.
Do they know?Did you tell them?
You're just full ofquestions, aren't you?
Well, of course I am.
I care about you.
I knew you were unhappy, but...
How did you know?
By asking questions.
Always asking, asking.
Everything you know,you pried right out of me.
Here's a thought...
Why don't you let  me  coachfigure skating tonight?
The kids are with your mom.
Have a night in, relax.
No, you relax.Figure skating is
on  my  schedule andwhether my daughter is
in attendance or not,I'll be there.
Ally, I think youneed some "me" time.
And I think you need to giveme my house keys back.
What?!What have I done?
Keys, please.
I know you're in pain,
so I won't askfor my keys back,
but I want you to know I won't
abandon you, Ally.
You know...
I'm afraid restoringyour brother's, uh,
appendage wasout of the question.
The tail was too badly damaged.
Must've been a new one for you.
Yes, but fascinating, actually.
That level of surgicalenhancement...
He's very committed.
How long do you expectto keep him here?
Between the blood lossand the risk
of infectionin that... area,
a few days to a week.
Thanks, doc.
I'll wait 'til he comes to.
Where are you with Cosima?
Closer.
She...
She made a pass at me, Aldous.
Really?
Yes.
Delphine,
Cosima's safety is at stake.
Other subjects, too.
I need to know
which ones she'sin contact with.
But  she  has toinitiate disclosure.
I'm not saying disclose.
This is a direct threat,so I need you
to dig deeper and faster.
"Dear Mummy
I miss you.
Mrs. S. Says you
are in the sunshine...
Please come home.
Love,
Kira".
Oi! Can you not,please?
I'm not going tohole up with you,
if you can't sit still.
Does it smell?
Yeah! It smellslike a foot.
Only worse, because it's yours.
Alison's not picking up.
Who's calling?
Art. Again.
Sorry, Beth doesn'tlive here anymore.
No, she lives with me.
So does herboytoy bodyguard.
Stop! Would youplease stop!
Pl...
Oi-oi, Mrs S.
Oi-oi.
And you're alive.
Yeah. Why?
Two homicide detectiveson my doorstep this morning,
quite convinced they'dfound  your  body
in a gravel quarry.
Who wants mimosas?
Sit down and shut your gob!
I was temptedto claim the remains
and feed themto you both on toast.
Would you care to enlighten me?
I don't want to lie to you, so,
not yet.
What'd they say?
Very little.
I'd venture littleis all they have.
Thanks.
Whatever is going on,if it takes
one step towards Kira,you need to yell fire.
The home we've builtfor ourselves
in this country,
we burn it all down,if we have to.
That's a promise.
Hey.
Hey, facial reconstruction'scoming along.
Yeah, well, hang onto your hat.
Sounds promising.
Sarah Manning offedherself, jumped in front
of a train at Huxley Station.
What?!
Check out the time of death.
Two days beforeJane Doe was shot.
Jane Doe can't beSarah Manning.
Sarah Manning was already dead.
Except, the prints match.
Twins, right? Twins.Twins' prints are
close enough to flag a match.
I mean, environmentalfactors like
wear and tear canusually differentiate.
Okay, but the fostermother said no relations.
That she knew of.
Sarah was an orphan.
Say Beth's a triplet,separated at birth.
Come on, humor me.Over a couple of days,
same city, one suicides,the other gets whacked?
I mean, it suggeststhey're in touch,
that they're not separateanymore, right?
And there's only oneleft to clear it up.
Beth!
Hey. Got yourmessages.
Bad time?
So what's this all about?
You miss me already?
Some questions came upabout your work
on the Jane Doe case.
Such as?
Well, you told us there was
no print match on the victim.
Yeah, there wasn't.
Well, there's noconfirmation of that
in the case file.
There should be.
Well, we ran them againand we got a match.
So, we're finallygetting somewhere.
Yeah, it sounds like it.
Just need to know...
Is this a joke?
Does the name
Sarah Manningmean anything to you?
Who the hell is this?
You've never seen her before?
Uh, uh, yeah, yeah,
in the mirror.
Come on. No!
Hey, I guess peoplehave lookalikes.
Do they?
Alison!
Alison, how are you?
Hmm?
Oh, poor hon.
If you need anything,just call.
Why can't youjust support me
in what I'm trying to do?This is important to me.
You can't just put onan outfit and be a coach.
You're not their coach. Youdon't know what you're doing.
- I am here every single...- Ally! Hey!
Hi, Chad.
Singlehood.Free at last, huh?
What are you doinghere, Aynsley?
I know, right?
Chad, go playwith your dumbbells.
I told you I'vegot this covered.
You're in no conditionto be coaching kids.
Way to rub saltin the wounds, Ayns.
Sorry, I tried.
I'm perfectly fineand no one asked you
to sub for me, so leave.
Alison, you're madat Donnie, not me.
I told you to stayaway from me.
And I told youyou're not yourself.
I know what you'redoing, Aynsley.
You want to mess with my life?
I'm going to mess with yours.
Sorry to be a bitch, here,
but it looks like you buried
Jane Doe's fingerprintsto hide your connection.
What connection?
I don't have a sister.
I don't knowwho this person is.
Sarah Manning was an orphan.
Same prints asJane Doe, but she
killed herself days beforeJane Doe was murdered.
Look, Beth,
we just need to knowwhere you fit in.
Can I see her file?
Sorry,
you're a civilian.
Yeah, what you always wanted.
Art, do I needto lawyer up, here?
I don't know, Beth.
Do you?
Have forensics run her prints
as fast as possible.
You got it.
Oh, shit.
Okay, fine, you caught me.
Just please don't narcon me to Aynsley.
You know how apeshit she getsabout stuff like this.
Whoa.
Alison.
You know, Chad,this is the first hit
I've had since"Godspell" in college.
I don't know what that is.
Okay.
You got any more?
Paul.
Dr. Aldous Leekiewill be here
in a couple hours.
He texted you.
You are conspiring
with at least two clones.
Just one, actually.
Are you crazy?
Despite appearances,I'm not the one
in a compromisingposition, here, Paul.
You blackmailed
an ex-military-intelligence guy
to do your dirty work.
Olivier Duval...
that's a classy pseudonym, bro.
Thank you.
Your real name is Kevin;
you're from Wenatchee,Washington;
and you have a raftof unsavory sex warrants.
The organization knows that.
Yeah, but the police don't.
And that's why you'regoing to listen
when I tell you whathappened last night.
Oh, I get it.
Smoke through the roof...
Accelerated dissipation.
Mm.
Mm-hmm.
Fewer air fresheners required.
Speaking of fresh air...
cheers to finallygetting Donnie
off your couch.
Are you mocking the failure
of my marriage, Chad?
Sorry.
No, don't be.
I gather you and Aynsley
aren't exactly booking nooners.
Eh, you know,
the thing about youand me, Hendrix...
Hmm?
We're sharks... we stopmoving, we die.
Hmm.
Well, you certainlygot that down.
Those late-night runsin your sleeveless tees.
You ain't so bad yourself.
Tight glutes.
Nice pecs.
I bet you could benchpress me.
Easy.
Bet you could bounce melike a ball.
Okay.
Maybe you've had too much.
Hmm.
Maybe you haven't had enough.
What are we doing, here?
I'm objectifying you.
Sexually.
To get back at Donnie.
I should really havea problem with this.
But you don't.
Hey, Delphine.
I hope I'm not disturbing you.
Oh, no no no.No, impossible.
So, apparently,I've got this thing
for, like, jumpingto conclusions.
You know, it's justthat I've never...
I know, I know,I know, you're not gay
and I'm a total idiot.
So sorry.
Oh, let me...
Oh, yes.
- Do you...?- Yeah.
I just want to make, like,
crazy science with you.
Totally crazy science.
I'm so glad to hear thatbecause you know what?
I was reading upon the Dyad Institute
and did you knowthat, Dr. Leekie,
he has builta dedicated department
for transgenic organtransplants? And...
Sorry, I was justdorking out so hard
to their extrapolationof murine models.
What?!
Yeah.
Oh, wow.
You know, it's really,really good
to finally meetsomeone who gets it.
Hmm.
Who gets me.
Yeah, ditto.
Obvs.
I can't stop thinkingabout that kiss.
Like ina not-bad way?
Oh, like
I've never thoughtabout bisexuality.
I mean, for myself, you know?
But as a scientist, I know that
sexuality is a spectrum.
But, you know, social biases,
they codified attraction.
It's contrary to thebiological facts,
you know?
Mm-hmm. That'soddly romantic.
Totally encouraging.
Oh, God!
You want meto coach, yeah!
Come on!Yeah!
Okay, no.
Let's turn aroundright here now.
Coach, yeah!
You're in the end zone.Yeah, you're my coach!
Touchdown!
♪ When I start to make you nervous ♪
♪ and I'm going to extremes ♪
♪ tomorrow, I will change ♪
♪ and todaywon't mean a thing ♪
♪ I'm a bitch, I'm a lover ♪
♪ I'm a child, I'm a mother ♪
♪ I'm a sinner, I'm a saint ♪
♪ I do not feel ashamed ♪
♪ I'm your hell,I'm your dream ♪
♪ I'm nothing in between ♪
♪ you know youwouldn't want it ♪
♪ any other way, yeah ♪
Get out!
Meera saw youscrewing my husband!
Everyone knows!
You screwed my husband!
Well, maybe, if you paid
more attention to  him and less to me.
Get out of the car, Alison!
You have
no idea who you'redealing with!
No, I know exactly who you are.
You're a sleazy watcher/spy.
Sleazy?
That's rich,
coming from a backstabbing
psycho  slut!
Like you.Do you...
Stop it!
Hey!
♪ And don't try to change me ♪
Ha-ha!
Aah!  ♪ I'm a bitch,I'm a lover ♪
♪ I'm a child, I'm a mother ♪
♪ I'm a sinner, I'm a saint ♪
♪ I do not feel
Hey hey hey,
morguee.
We need everything you goton Sarah Manning.
Caucasian female,suicide by train.
You processed thebody and its release.
I process lotsof bodies.
Is there a problem?
Fingerprints from our Jane Doe
of the gravel crusher.
Forensics says they'respooky-close
to two other women.
Yeah, one's Sarah Manning.
The other is a...totally other woman.
Let's see.Uh...
Sarah Manning.Suicide by train.
Holy shit.
It's uncanny.
We need the nameand the address
of the person whoidentified her.
What?! I...
Okay, Colin, please slow down.
What, exactly, did they say?
I couldn't lie, Felix, okay?
There are records.Your signature, address.
Okay,
I've got to go,
but you just take a hot bath.
I'll talk to you later.
Shit! Sarah.
You can handle this, yeah?
Cops? Yeah.I... yeah.
Where are you going to go?
No idea.
Shit!
Felix!
It's me, Alison!
Please be home.
You're effing kidding me.
Bad things have happened to me.
And I would loveto hear about them,
I would, but, right now,
you need to go.
What?
I can't go back there.
It's just for onenight, Alison.
I slept with Aynsley's husband.
What?
I shagged Chad.
Then Aynsley attacked me
in the middle of the street.
I degraded myself
and I disgraced my children
and I can't go back there.
I seriously underestimated you.
I hope you kicked her arse.
I did.
Kind of.
I don't want to divorce Donnie,
but I can't keep lyingto him and I hate
lying to my kids, I hate it!
How can we possiblysustain this insanity?
We can't.
I don't know if Art'sgoing to throw me in jail
or if Cosima's going tonarc us out
to the Neolutionists, or what.
Don't forget Helena.She's always fun.
All I know is I cameback to fix things,
be a real mum to Kira.
So what if we tell them?
You mean come out?
"I miss you
Mummy".
"I miss you Mummy."
"I miss youMummy."
Scotsburn Avenue.
148.
Dr. Baker to pediatrics, please.
Dr. Baker.
I replaced yoursecurity footage
to show only one clone.
Beth... Sarah...Was never there.
He's smart.It won't work.
It will, if you stick to one.
There was only one.
And you needto stop blaming yourself.
How could you know?
Uh,
Dr. Leekie,I'm...
Paul Dierden.
I hear great things.
Aldous.
Aldous, she took my tail.
Shut up, Olivier.
Are you okay?
Yes.
Are you sure?
I...I cry after sexwith boys, too.
Poor you.
But you know what?
Hmm?
I am never this hungry.
I could killfor some ice cream.
Mmm. Okay.
Your wish is my command.
I'm going to goto the store and I'm
going to get ussome Eskimo Pies.
Eskimo?
Yeah.
I don't think I know it.
- No?- No.
Prepare yourself.
You're about to becomea craven addict.
I think I already am.
Merde.
She dropped the Beth actcold right in front of us.
If it weren't for Paul,she would've killed me.
She said her name was Helena
and she had an accent,slavic.
She admitted she killed Beth
and took over her life.
Aldous, she iscompletely insane.
Welcome to the big picture.
Yes, sir.
Sorry, guys.
Visiting hours are over.
Oh, sure. We'll getout of your way.
You just rest and heal.
What do they sayin the military,
"you've proven your mettle"?
No, sir, nobody ever said that.
Okay.
Well, tomorrow,
I'd like to talkabout next steps.
Excuse me.
Found something?
Promise me Cosima's safe.
Her quest, Aldous,it's all perfectly...
perfectly natural.
Delphine,
believe me, I'm protecting her.
Now, what is it?
Well, she's not onlyresearching her own biology,
but she is aware of...of eight others.
She's had contact.
I need names.
Okay, yes. Well, someof them seem to be dead.
- Janika Zingler.- Yes.
Danielle Fournier.
Yes.
Katja Obinger.
Helena. There is no last name.
Helena.
There's Alison Hendrix,Beth Childs,
and Sarah Manning.
Sarah Manning?
Anything else on her?
No, nothing.
Listen, I have to go.She's coming. Bye.
Phew.
Hello?
What happened?Are you okay?
Yeah. It's time,Siobhan.
Time I told you what'sreally going on.
Well, then, I am all ears.
Siobhan, this isAlison hendrix.
Pleased to meet you.
Well, tell me more, love.
I mean, it can'tget any stranger
than human cloning.
Well, we live in Scarborough.
About a million years ago,
I went to university.
You went to university?
Mm! Yes.Kinesiology.
Where'd you go wrong?
Oh, that's just basicallymassage therapy, in't it?
No, Sarah.
It's very important.
It heals.
Oh!
No.
Um, and then I got married.
And everything is shit.
She cameto see Kira once,
in your place, didn't she?
I  knew  something was up.
Yeah, sorry, the crazy one,Helena, was after me.
Okay, so, Helena,Alison, Cosima.
Beth is the policewoman.
Yeah, who topped herself, yeah.
You.
No, there's probablythousands of us.
Ahem! Unless Helena'skilled them all.
We're all messed up.
Except you, Sarah.
I'm the biggest messthere is, Alison.
No, no no no, becauseyou say "eff it".
I triedto say "eff it" today
and I blew up my whole life.
I just wantedto say "eff this",
"eff you", and I effed it,
I effed it all up.
Oh.
You know,would you like to see
the guest bedroom,at this point, chicken?
Huh? Huh?Come on.
Yes. Oh, you areso lovely.
Ahem! You know, you'revery lucky, Sarah.
My mother wouldn't bethis lovely. She...
My mother would have meput in therapy.
Yeah, yes.
That's Sarah.
Whew.
I was just so shocked.
Seeing her laid outon that slab,
looking so
dead, really.
So your foster sisterdidn't have any sisters?
Just me.
I keep asking myself
"What'd I miss?",you know?
Because I never reallysaw the signs.
Beth Childs.
Hmm?Who's that?
You mind if I look?
I like art.
No, yeah, by all means.
Oh! Uh...
Those are
the many sides of Sarah.
I call that series
twisted sister.
I like 'em.
Sort of working out your grief.
Yes.
Wherever it takes me.
Thanks.
I'm sorry, again,
for your loss.
Thank you.
I've been here before.
What does that mean?
Hello.
Hello?
Harvey, you pervy bastard,
i know that's you.
Last night, I get a phone call.
Some punk withan English accent
says he wantsto talk about Beth.
Then he hangs up.
Let's bring him in. Let'sshake his tree, man.
Nah, it's too early.I want to get
a better picture of thiswhole deal, first.
Come on.
What are you doing?
Any loss of sensationin your feet?
No.
Just checking.
Get some rest.
Oh, and Dr. Leekiesends his regards.
I knowthere's more here,
between the lines.
What is it thatyou need, Sarah?
How can I help?
Wow,
Alison, Cosima, Beth...
Their mothers all wanted babies
enough to do in vitro.
So why did mine give me up?
There were
rumors.
Yeah?
That some of the kidswe were hiding,
the ones that camein Carlton's pipeline,
like you, childrenin the black...
What do you mean,
exactly, "in the black"?
You know, undocumented.
Outside the system.
The rumor was these kids
were the subject ofmedical experiments.
Carlton's pipeline.
What kind of experiments?
I don't know, love.
It was a paranoid timeand a radical fringe.
Everything was rumor then.
Carlton brought me to you.
Wouldn't he knowwho my birth mother was?
He may. But,even if he did,
he might not tell  me.
Do your contactsstill know him?
It-it's possible.
Can you get in touch with him?
It's 15 years ago.
Last I heard, he was inWormwood Scrubs Prison.
I'll try.
I just want to know who I am.
You're still you.
Remember that.
You're a survivor.
Kira?
It's Helena!Kira!
Kira!
Where are we going?
I'm taking you to meet someone.
How can you be Sarah'sdaughter, child?
How can that be?
Kira!
Stop!
You're just like my mum.
No, I'm not.
She's not real.
Of course she is.
Kira!
Helena?
Yes, angel?
What happened to you?
I don't know.
Kira!
I should go home now.
Yes.
Do you know the way?
Of course.
Goodnight, angel.
Kira!
Mummy!
Kira, no!
No!
7-year-old femalestruck by vehicle.
GCS 3.Chest injury.
Possible internal bleeding.
- Stay with me, baby, please.- 3 minutes.
Bet you 100 bucks I know whoshe's going to look like
when Beckwith is donewith the reconstruction.
You got no chargethat'll stick, yet.
- Why is Sarah still alive?- Kill her!
Someone tampered withthe security footage
at Club Neolution
but I know
there were two clonesthere that night.
Weren't there?
- Oh, my God!- Alison.
What is this?
We're gathered in the spirit
of love and understanding.